JESSICA CLAIRE

- resumesample@example
- (555) 432-1000,
- Montgomery Street, San Francisco, CA 94105

- •

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

HUMAN RESOURCES GENERALIST Extensive background in HR generalist affairs, including experience in employee recruitment and retention, staff development, mediation, conflict resolution, benefits and compensation, HR records management, HR policies development and legal compliance. Demonstrated success in negotiating win-win compromises, developing teambuilding programs, and writing personnel manuals, corporate policies, job descriptions and management reports.

CORE QUALIFICATIONS

- HR Department Startup
- Employment Law
- FMLA/ADA/EEO/WC
- Mediation & Advocacy
- HR Policies & Procedures St Recruitment & Retention
- **Employee Relations**
- Alternative Dispute Resolut (ADR)
- Benefits Administration
- HR Program/Project Manag Orientation & On-Boarding
- HRIS Technologies
- Training & Development
 Development
- Performance Management
- Organizational Development

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF TEXAS AT ARLINGTON

Arlington, TX • 2011 – –

Bachelor of Arts (BA): Psycho Industrial Organization - GPA: Psychology Industrial Organiza

, • – –

Worked full-time for Robert Half International as HR administrator, 2010-2012 HR Designations: PHR (Professional in Human Resources), Eligible 2015: - GPA:

EXPERIENCE

Idex Corporation - HR Manager

Vancouver, WA, • • 01/2014 - Current

- Provides unarmed/armed guard services to commercial buildings and government accounts.
- Recruited to help expand Texas operation, guiding the management of a full spectrum of HR operations, systems and programs.
- Worked with senior management to create HR policies and procedures; recruit employees; and develop orientation, training and incentive programs.
- Manage leave-of-absence programs and personnel records; administer benefits enrollment and programs; and handle HR generalist workplace issues.
- Key Results: Played a key role in ensuring the successful expansion of Dallas
 office.
- Structured and implemented programs and policies in the areas of training, benefits packages, incentives and new-employee orientation.
- Fostered an open-door environment conducive to positive dialogue across the organization.
- Personal efforts were cited as the driving force behind branch's employeeretention rate of 89% within an industry where high turnover is the norm.
- Negotiated approximately 50 salary offers and dozens of sign-on bonuses annually at both the exempt and nonexempt level.
- Reduced benefits costs through meticulous recordkeeping and ensuring that company did not pay for benefits for which employees were ineligible.
- Revised job descriptions across all levels and categories.
- Shadowed" and interviewed employees to construct an accurate picture of the duties and skills required for each position.
- Brought workers' compensation program to full compliance, by working directly with insurance representative to identify possible workplace dangers.

American Addiction Centers - HR Generalist/Recruiter

Orange County, CA, • • 01/2013 - 01/2014

- Leading supplemental insurance company employing 2,500 professionals.
- Fulfilled a broad range of HR functions, including recruiting and training employees, administering benefits, assisted in benefit renewal, overseeing continuing education program and managing HR records.
- Coordinated health fairs to promote employee wellness and performed exit interviews.
- Key Results: Trained four-member management team on interviewing techniques and best practices, conducting workshops and one-on-one coaching sessions that contributed to sound hiring decisions.
- Developed company's first-ever standardized Emergency Evacuation procedures and tracking system that insulated company from legal risk and ensured consistent processes in case of emergency.
- Co-wrote employee manual covering issues including disciplinary procedures, code
 of conduct, FMLA policy and benefits information.
- Devised creative and cost-effective incentive and morale-boosting programs (including special events and wellness program) that increased employee satisfaction and productivity.
- Reworked new-hire orientation program to include HR information and company resources.
- Saved company thousands of dollars annually by reducing reliance on employment agencies.
- Brought the majority of formerly outsourced recruiting functions in-house to reduce billable hours from 200+ to less than 15 per month.

Parker-Hannifin, Corporation - HR Leader Mansfield, TX, • • 01/2012 - 01/2013

 Nationally recognized hotels and resorts Extensively trained in all facets of HR functions, including recruiting and training employees, administering benefits,

- assisting in workers' compensation investigations and claims.

 Managing incentive programs and personnel records.
- Coordinating special events and performed exit interviews

- Key Results: Assisted in the revision of employee manual covering issues including company policies and code of conduct.
- Trained senior management and new employees on Omni culture and continuing education.
- Part of Associate Services Team to improve employee engagement survey average from 3.8% to 4.2%.
- Reduced average number of job openings by half, reducing turnover by 22%.

PROFESSIONAL AFFILIATIONS

Society for Human Resource Management (SHRM)

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

 Complete ongoing training in the areas of compensation and benefits, employee and labor relations, leaves of absence, workers' compensation and workplace safety/security.

LANGUAGES

Spanish (Fluent)

SKILLS

ADA, ADR, benefits, Benefits Administration, coaching, driving, Employee Relations, special events, senior management, government, hiring, HRIS, Human Resources, HR, HUMAN RESOURCE, insurance, Languages, Law, Iegal, Managing, Mediation, office, Organizational Development, Performance Management, personnel, Policies, processes, Project Management, Recruitment, recruiting, sound, Spanish, Structured, training employees, workshops